### Ranjan Ekanayake

173 Lucy Ln, San Ramon, CA 94582



Email: rpekanayake@gmail.com
Profile: www.academiflow.com

Phone: (904) 200-9287 (C)

### **OBJECTIVE**

Experienced Sr. Full Stack Engineer skilled in designing and deploying scalable web applications. Proficient in modern frontend and back-end technologies, delivering user-focused solutions that drive business success. Seeking to contribute expertise in software architecture and agile development to a dynamic team.

### **SUMMARY**

I have over a decade of experience building multi-tier web and portal applications for Intranet and Internet use, utilizing modern front-end and back-end technologies. During this period, I performed various tasks, including Business Analyst, System Analyst, UX/UI design, Client-side, and Server-side development, across monolithic, SOA, and Microservice architectures. During my career, I have worked in various industries, namely health services, human resources, and property title insurance.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Applications: EditPlus, TextPad 5, HomeSite, Dreamwever, MSOffice2010 Professional, WordPerfect, Adobe

PhotoShop 5.0-6.0, Adobe ImageReady 2.0, Acrobat Exchange, ImageStyler, MS Outlook, etc

Frameworks/Libs: Angular/Material, React, Redux, RxJS, Next.js, Auth.js, Jest, Jasmine/Karma, JUnit, Mockito,

GWT, Java, Spring, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Swagger/OpenAPI, Thymeleaf, Node.Js, Django, Express.js, Redis, Docker, Docker Compose, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Shadcn-UI, ReChart.js,

Chart.js

Databases: MongoDB/MongoDB Shell, Dynamo DB, MySQL 8.1, PostgreSQL, UDB, DB2, Oracle7-11

Case Tools: GitHub Copilot, ChatGPT, ER-Win, InfoModeler, Salsa, Visio, System Architect

Programming: Java 17, JavaScript ES6, Typescript 5, Python 3, EJB's, JMS, Java/Beans, Servlets, SQL,

PL/SQL, HTML, SCSS, XML/XSL/JAXP/JAXB, Eclipse, Unix Shell (bash, ksh, csh, tcsh), Perl, CGI

IDE's: IntelliJ, NetBeans 8, VS Code, PyCharm, Eclipse, RAD 7, WSAD 6.0

Scripting: JavaScript ES6, Bash scripting, JSF, AJAX, jQuery, Struts, JSTL & Custom Tags,

XSLT/XPath/XML/XSD/DTD, JSP, JSON, YAML, Flex, Ant 1.6, Unix Shell

Web/App Servers: Apache Tomcat 8, WebSphere 7.0-5.0, WebLogic 5.0-7.0, ATG Dynamo 4.5-6.0

Other Tools: Hibernate, PayPal, Stripe, Mongoose, Vite, Webpack, Drizzle, Maven, Clear Case, Clear Quest,

PVCS, CVS, VSS, Sql Developer, SQL Navigator, MySQL Workbench, CC, Jprofiler, Putty 6

Services: AWS, Gemini, GitHub Copilot, ChatGPT, OAuth2, OpenID Connect, REST API, FastAPI, Axis 2.1,

JAX-RPC/SOAP Web Services, JDBC, Logger, LDAP, JNDI, JMS, JTA, SMTP mail, Junit 5.0 testing

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### iRhythm Technologies Inc., San Francisco, CA Sr. Software Engineer (Full-Time)

02/2014 - 09/2024 02/2014 - 09/2024

Tech Stack:

Java 11/17, Hibernate 5, Spring 5.0, Spring Boot 3, EHR, REST/SOAP WS, GWT, Angular 17/React 18, Redux, RxJS, Node.js, Express.js, HTML, TypeScript, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS/SCSS, Python, YAML, Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Jira, Confluence, Bamboo, Docker, Spring Cloud, Microservices, AWS services. MySQL 8, MongoDB 6/Mongoose.

- Gathered business requirements and designed prototypes with an eye on UX.
- Prototype user screens with user experience design in mind using Figma, Visio
- Worked on Angular/material, OAuth2, OpenID Connect, REST API, RxJS, Typescript, GWT, HTML. JavaScript, CSS, SCSS Client-side external/internal apps
- Worked on Python Jinja2, Java REST, and MySQL using a full-stack MyZio web application.
- Implemented Client-side and Server-Side REST/SOAP style Web services.
- Write unit test code using Junit, Mockito, Jasmin
- Build and deploy application war in Tomcat 6/7/8 local server and cloud using Bamboo.
- Write DDL/DML scripts for backend MySQL DB
- Use MongoDB/Mongoose operations in a React internal app
- Persist data in Salesforce client via SOAP WS and interact with Salesforce UI client.

## Ranjan Ekanayake

173 Lucy Ln, San Ramon, CA 94582



Email: rpekanayake@gmail.com Profile: www.academiflow.com

Phone: (904) 200-9287 (C)

# Taleo Jacksonville, FL & Oracle Corporation Pleasanton, CA Oracle - Sr. Software Engineer, Pleasanton, CA Taleo -Java Developer III, Jacksonville, FL

**09/2011 - 11/2013**March 2012 - Nov. 2013
Sept. 2011 - March 2012

Tools Used:

Oracle ADF faces, JDeveloper, Java, J2EE, PHP, Facebook API, Lotus Notes 5.0, SQL Developer, EJB 3.0 HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, XML, AJAX, jQuery, JSP, JSF 2.0, Primefaces 2.0, Java 6.0, SWT, Hibernate 4, Eclipse, JDBC, Axis2, JAX-WS, JAX-RS, SOAP Web Services, Apache CXF, SOAP UI 4.6, Lotus Expeditor Toolkit 6, SWT, Swing, Window 7 Prof, /Unix Solaris, Tomcat 7, JBoss 7, WebLogic 12, Glassfish 4, Oracle 11g, Oracle Fussion App, JUnit, Fiddler, Ant, Maven4

- Develop pages for "NextGen" project utilizing ADF faces, JSF 2.0, JDeveloper, Eclipse, Spring/Hibernate, J2EE, Maven, Weblogic, Oracle
- Setup environment in Linux for Oracle Business Intelligent Enterprise (OBIE) SAAS enablement project, Tomcat, WebLogic, JBoss, Maven
- Maintained and enhanced new services for Lotus Notes client plug-in tool "Taleo Recruiting Application" Java, SWT, Swing, SOAP Axis2, CXF.
- Enhanced the existing Facebook social media "Taleo Job Openings" application utilizing PHP/Facebook API/JQuery/Ajax/Javascript.
- Self designed, developed, tested, and deployed "TextTool" JSF2.0/Primefaces /java/JAXB/WS app to produce multi-language XML file.
- Later converted the above application to work on the command line using ant, java, web services
- Work with Oracle, MySQL, databases and wrote backend SQL queries
- Built and deployed applications in Apache Tomcat, WebLogic, and JBoss application servers in Linux/windows
- Wrote technical documents about the development, and deployment of applications.

# Fidelity National Financial Inc., Jacksonville, FL Sr. Software Engineer

12/2005 - 01/2011

Tools Used:

Oracle 10g, Toad, ClearCase, ClearQuest, Visio, Rational Rose, HTML, JavaScript, ActionScript, CSS, XML, AJAX, JSP, JSF, XSLT/XPath, Flex/BlazeDS, Servlet, Java 5.0, Maia Framework(inhouse), MVC, JAX-RPC Web Services, J2EE (EJB) WAS 6/7, Eclipse 5, Ant 1.6, SQL Developer, Toad, Oracle, Junit, JDBC, JNDI, LDAP & Unix Solaris.

- Gathered business requirements
- System Analysis and Data Model Analysis of the Use Cases.
- Prototype user screens using Vizio.
- Implemented Client Side and Server Side JAX-RPC/SOAP style WebServices.
- Write unit test code using Junit
- Write backend SQL queries, tune SQL queries
- Write/Modify/Trouble-Shoot client side and server side complete life cycle code using the above tools
- Build and deploy application ear in WebSphere 6/7 local server.
- Install and configure development tools such as WebSphere 6/7 server, RAD, Eclipse IDE, Oracle, SQL Developer
   Transformed XML data to HTML/PDF formats using JAXB/XSL-FO/XSD/XSLT/XPath tools
- Used FLEX 3/ActionScript/BlazeDS technology and Java to persist data in a small Configuration Tool project.

### **EDUCATION**

### Eastern Michigan University, Ypsilanti, MI

M.S. in Computer Information Systems

### University of Maine, Orono, ME

M.S. in Food Science & Human Nutrition

### **TRAINING**

- Advanced React by Meta Certificate
- GraphQL with React Complete Developer Guide
- Next.is -The Complete Developer Guide Certificate
- Spring Boot 3, Spring 6 & Hibernate Full Stack Certificate
- Docker-Hands On for Java Developers

- Intermediate PostgreSQL by UMich Certificate
- Complete Angular Course 2024 Certificate
- Reactive Angular (RxJS) course Certificate